Wesley Street, GISP

Owasso, Oklahoma · wesley.street2016@gmail.com

Summary

Experienced geospatial professional with strong ArcGIS Enterprise and scripting skills • 18 years of experience as project manager and leader • customer service and communications experience • creative, innovative, and organized • TS/SCI w/ Poly

Experience

11/2021-

US Army Corps of Engineers

Tulsa, OK

Geospatial Data Manager (40 hrs/wk)

Develop a geospatial data strategy for the district within the standards of USACE. • Consolidate district portal with other districts in the division. • Create a standardized schema withing the Corps's adaptation of SDSFIE. • Manage enterprise geodatabases on SQL server. • Create standards for geospatial products within the district. • Work with ESRI on internal contracts and develop a customized training curriculum for the geospatial section.

12/2017-11/2021

National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency

St. Louis, MO

Geospatial Analyst (40 hrs/wk)

Use Portal for ArcGIS and ArcGIS Enterprise to create webapps for data creation, collaboration, and dissemination to diverse groups across the country. • Supervise and train a team of 25 analysts. • Stood up a GIS Roundtable of office Geospatial Analysts to discuss projects, data standards, and a community troubleshooting approach. • Create schema, domains, and feature classes within ArcGIS Enterprise to enforce data integrity and ease of analysis. • Founding member of office Data Governance Council. • Service enable community datasets. • Develop a good working relationship with ESRI and other vendors

Training: Fundamentals for Geospatial Analysis, Introduction to GEOINT, Fundamental of Intelligence Writing, Fundamental of Intelligence Briefing, Service Enabling Course

08/2016-12/2017

EASi Engineering

Tulsa, OK

GIS Specialist (08/2017-12/2017) (45 hrs/wk)

Served as lead for the GIS and transmission line engineering team with 4 editors, another specialist, and a technical writer at the Tulsa EASi office. • Filled the role of one of 5 required GIS Specialist within American Electric Power's Transmission Line Engineering Department. • Developed apps using Survey123, Collector for ArcGIS and other programs for disconnected and mobile editing. • Supported public open houses with GIS services • Conducted future planning as well as trouble shoot current issues within the GIS/IT framework. • Produced high quality, online GIS maps and applications as well as paper cartographic products. • Coordinated activities and efforts with other regional GIS specialists.

GIS Technician III (08/2016-08/2017) (40 hrs/wk)

Prepared and deployed projects to ArcGIS Online and ArcGIS for Portal • Served as a GIS SME for both internal employees as well as our client. • Wrote technical and user documentation for business processes. • Tested changes in development environment and trouble shoot bugs in production environment. • Coordinated GIS activities across our clients GIS infrastructure and with other GIS specialists.

01/2013-01/2016

Samson Energy Company

Tulsa, OK

GIS Analyst (40 hrs/wk)

Worked with our primary 3rd party vendor for GIS Add-in • Tested patches, builds, and identifying problems. • Worked with Oracle and SQL databases • Installed and tested GIS Extensions, Add-Ins, and tools to ensure conflict free deployments • Used Python to write scripts automating GIS tasks or streamline workflows from simple data creation to 3D

Wesley Street, GISP

Owasso, Oklahoma · wesley.street2016@gmail.com

directional well bores • Created new ArcGIS layers, assist in managing and updating ArcSDE and shapefiles • Worked with remote machines, servers, Citrix deployments and assist IT • Agreement mapping and performing QA/QC on existing agreements • Provided support for other GIS users in the company • Upgraded GIS Citrix and License Servers

01/2001-Present

United States Army Reserve

Sergeant First Class

Operations Chief/Combat Engineer (05/2016-present, 06/2009-08/2014)

Prepare operational intelligence, concepts of operations, and develop scheme of maneuver for combat patrols • Train Soldiers and Marines on use of DSGS and other GIS platforms • Supervise billeting and facilities maintenance for 91 soldiers, company offices, and motorpool • Organize training for soldiers with field service representatives to maintain and expand unit expertise • Provide their expertise in areas such as mobility, counter-mobility, survivability and general engineering to a multi-national task force • Conducted route reconnaissance and clearance, including interrogation and neutralization of Improvised Explosive Devices in Helmand Province, Afghanistan 2010-2011 and Parwan Province, Afghanistan 2019-2020

Civil Affairs Team Sergeant (08/2014-04/2016)

Identified critical requirements needed by local citizens in combat or crisis situations • responsible for researching, coordinating, conducting and participating in the planning and production of civil affairs related documents • enabled the civil-military operations of the supported commander

Construction Engineer/Supervisor (01/2001-06/2009)

Supervised construction projects for the Army • Used bulldozers, cranes, graders, tractors with dozer attachments, scoop loaders, backhoe loaders, hydraulic excavators, and other heavy equipment • Accountable for more than \$1-million of sensitive equipment: weapons, night vision equipment, emergency beacons and related maintenance. • Responsible for more than eight soldiers, their well-being, vehicles, and equipment. • Managed construction projects, personnel, and operated heavy construction equipment in Baghdad, Iraq 2008-2009

Training: Company Intelligence Support Team (COIST), Route Reconnaissance and Clearance (Sapper), ATF Level 1 Post Blast Analysis Certified, In-theater Blow-In-Place (IED Neutralization) certification, M160 Operator Course, Advanced Leaders Course, Warrior Leaders Course, Unit Prevention Leader, Armorer's course

Education/Certifications

2018-present

University of Wisconsin - Madison

Madison, WI

• Master of Science in Cartography/GIS (Development)

2016-2017 Missouri State University

Springfield, MO

• Graduate Certificate in Homeland Security and Defense

06-2012 Missouri State University Springfield, MO

- Bachelor of Science in Geospatial Science
- Undergraduate GIS Certificate

2017 GIS Certification Institute

• GIS Professional Certification

2013 American Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing

• Certified Mapping Scientist, GIS/LIS (Provisional, pending conformation of work experience)

2013-2018 ESRI Training

Wesley Street, GISP

Owasso, Oklahoma · wesley.street2016@gmail.com

- ArcGIS Enterprise: Configuring a Base Deployment (2018)
- ArcGIS Server: Site Configuration and Administration (2018)
- Configuring Web Apps Using Web AppBuilder for ArcGIS (2018)
- Introduction to Geoprocessing Scripts Using Python (2013)